Welcome to our video on Step 1 B of Send to Amazon, a streamlined shipment workflow that
saves you time by simplifying fulfillment by Amazon or FBA shipment creation.
In this video, you'll learn steps to provide box content information and pack individual
units from Step 1 of the workflow.
You won't see this step on Seller Central's Send to Amazon page if you already provided
box content information for all your SKUs using the case-pack templates in Step 1.
Once you've confirmed the quantity of individual units to send to Amazon, we determine which
SKUs can be packed together based on whether they require special handling at our fulfillment
centers.
For example, SKUs that are categorized as Dangerous Goods or Hazmat can't be packed
with other SKUs.
That's because Dangerous Goods are shipped to special fulfillment centers that can receive
them safely.
Two other factors that determine which SKUs can be packed together are product weights
and dimensions.
Also, over-sized SKUs can't be packed with standard-sized SKUs.
That's because over-sized SKUs can only be received at specialized fulfillment centers.
Finally, SKUs that require prep or labeling to be performed by Amazon shouldn't be packed
with SKUs that are already prepped and labeled.
This ensures that boxes containing SKUs that don't require Amazon to prep or label them
aren't unnecessarily sidelined at the fulfillment center and can be made available to customers
sooner.
Once your pack groups are determined, you'll be prompted to provide box content information
for the SKUs in each pack group.
In this example, inventory has been sorted into two pack groups.
You can pack SKUs in a pack group in any combination.
However, you shouldn't mix SKUs from one pack group with SKUs from another pack group.
If all units in a pack group fit into one box, select everything will fit into one box and
click Confirm.
Then enter the box weight and dimensions and click Confirm Packing Information.
If the units in a pack group will be packed in more than one box, select multiple boxes
will be needed and click Confirm.
Next, provide packing information for your multiple boxes.
From the drop down menu, you have three options.
The enter through a web form option lets you enter box content information individually
using a web form.
The Upload Excel File option lets you efficiently upload box content information in bulk.
The Amazon Manually Processes Box Contents option lets you choose to outsource this step
and have Amazon provide this service for a per unit fee.
Select enter through a web form if you have less than 12 units.
Next, enter the estimated number of boxes and click Open Web Form.
Then enter your box content information.
Here, you'll enter the units boxed, box weight and box dimensions.
Then click Confirm Packing Information.
For more guidance, click Instructions or Need Help in the top right corner.
Select Upload Excel File to efficiently upload box content information in bulk.
Then enter the estimated number of boxes that the SKUs in a pack group will fit into.
Next click Generate Excel File.
Download the template and open the file in Excel.
For each box, enter the number of units of each SKU that you'll be packing in that box.
Make sure that the quantity of units in the boxes for each SKU is equal to the expected
quantity of SKUs in that box.
Next enter the box weight and dimensions.
As you pack, mark your boxes as Pack Group 1 Box 1, Pack Group 1 Box 2 and so on.
This will help you match the right FBA Box ID label to each box in step 3, Print Box
Labels.
After you're done packing your shipping boxes and entering the information in the Excel
file, save the file and upload it to Send to Amazon by clicking Upload and Validate File.
We understand that as you pack your boxes, you might want to change the quantity of certain
SKUs to account for damaged inventory or to optimize the space inside one or more boxes.
You can do so by going back to step 1 and updating the quantity of SKUs that you want
to send.
When you're done, proceed to step 1B.
Note that the pack groups can change when you add or remove SKUs in step 1.
Make sure that you re-upload the box content information for updated pack groups.
After you provide box content information for all pack groups, click Confirm and Continue
to proceed to the next step.
This concludes the instructional video for step 1B, Pack Individual Units.
In the next step, we'll determine the optimal location for your boxes to be sent so they're as close
to your customers as possible.
Check out the video for step 2 Confirm Shipping in Seller University.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.